2020 we had a fall and then the markets
bounc back and there seems to be no
stopping uh that rally and over a period
of time we start hearing uh you know
sound bites like the market is expensive
which the P ratios are you know at
unprecedented Highs valuations are at
unprecedented highs and that sort of
troubles some of the investors because
typically when the market is rising uh
the way it did from March April of 2020
uh all stocks and all Investments go up
whether they have value or they don't
have value so it's also a time where
something which was underperforming
previously has now started doing well
there is some profit now on the table uh
and the worry is that even though I have
more money uh to invest uh is there a is
there a likely sort of Crash and a dimin
and value of my investment likely to
take place so people think that yes it's
a good time to uh you know take money
off the table of course for those
investors who have requirements of the
fund or they are genuinely following
asset allocation and finding a higher
Equity allocation than what they are
comfortable with it's a good idea to
pull uh pull out uh some of their
profits uh but I would certainly
recommend that people and investors look
at their goals uh their risk profiles
what are they going going to do with the
money that's going to come out as long
as they are clear about all of that only
then go ahead and say I must redeem
across the
board okay well you should be having a
plan really of what you're going to do
with your uh the money that you are
redeeming from these Equity mutual funds
yes markets are high and you can be
tempted to take some money off but then
have a plan of what you're going to do
the other Cas is of course if your goals
are coming closer then that's another
reason why you should consider redeeming
your mutual funds okay uh you know large
cap funds have actually seen more
redemptions even small cap funds as
perhaps investors were put up by the
correction seen there um so how are you
looking at small and midcap funds right
now Mr naui because you know what's
interesting is that midcap funds have
actually seen net flows coming in but
large and small caps we've seen money
being taken off right now so what would
be your strategy uh you know especially
for a new investor where should they put
their money large caps midcaps and small
caps and also for existing large cap
midcap small Cap Fund holders what do
you
recommend yeah so I I think it's uh
typically when you're are investing in
equity you have to keep in mind longer
time Cycles to get the returns so if I'm
investing in a large cap type of fund
Blue Chip stocks then typically a 3 to
5e cycle is the is the time over which I
will truly
uh sort of generate my returns uh once I
move into midcap they tend to be a
little more volatile and therefore you
need to give them five to seven years
when you go to small cap you possibly
need to give them 7 to 10 years uh time
Horizon for you to realize your sort of
gains so we must understand that small
caps are small caps because they have
not been uh recognized by everybody by
all Market players uh so the blue chips
are the are the top names that everybody
has heard of so there is no real
Discovery to happen and there are 100
stocks which are defined as large gap
there are 150 stocks defined as as
midcap when you go to small cap
everything beyond the 250 are small cap
so the the the basket from where I will
pick winners is much much larger and
therefore selection uh of of those
stocks become very very important so
keep that in mind before you determine
how you need to allocate the second
thing is you asked about existing
investors now an existing investor has
seen very good returns in the market uh
over the last one year uh and in in you
know till a few days ago the small cap
index had given double the returns of a
large cap index so while a large cap
index had given 45% 50% type of return
uh in small cap you had more than 100%
return a little while ago
uh and that of course was on the back of
Falls that had happened in the prior two
years so your allocation between large
cap midcap small cap needs to be thought
of U you know almost like constructing a
building so there is a foundation which
needs to be strong before you decide
whether you are going to build two
floors five floors or 20 floors in the
building uh so your that core on the
foundation really needs to be large cap
so one would recommend you know a larger
portion of your investment is in that
core part of portfolio and then to get
generate that little extra return for
with the quantum that you have available
for longer periods of time that's when
you allocate to midcap and small
cap all right okay understood I want to
talk about some more uh you know uh fund
categories where we are seeing a lot of
interest one of them is the flexi cap
funds um look at the momentum over there
uh of course the the net inflows has
also been further egged on because we
have had a few nfos in that category but
that you know the fact that mutual fund
houses are launching nfos is because
also they believe that investors have a
big appetite for this what's your take
on flexi cap funds because you know
there's no clear category that okay this
belongs to large cap midcap or small cap
they're free to invest across market
caps so how do you view this fund
category uh in terms of its riskiness
its suitability as well for investors
with different risk profiles
yeah and I think the first thing is that
fund houses are launching nfos because
investors are having the money to invest
uh and therefore they are trying to
attract them to invest through an nfo
route uh in the flexi cap funds I I
think they are really for a more sort of
educated more mature investors or
investors who are using a financial
advisor uh the reason is that the flexi
Cap Fund really
leaves uh each of the fund managers free
to decide what Quantum of their money
needs to be in large gap what needs to
be in midcap what needs to be in small
cap and to move things around within
those different market capitalizations
now unless you have a really well U well
equipped fund manager a very well
equipped team a bunch of analysts within
the fund house you might not get these
sort of calls correct as to where your
weightages should be so I think it is
really only for people who understand
this this element uh some of the flexy
cap funds have even started
incorporating International exposure
within their uh their sort of basket and
therefore give you that little feel that
oh you know apart from just vanilla ice
cream there's some you know chocolate
sauce and a cherry also on the top so
will that help in terms ter of my
getting some exposure internationally um
so those are sort of different ways by
which I think flexi cap fund managers
are attracting uh investors to come in I
think you should just take it with a bit
of caution because as I mentioned in the
last one year if my small cap return is
double that of large cap any flexi Cap
Fund which has had more weightage to
small cap will show much much better
performance than a fund which has
decided that no I'd rather have a larger
component in large cap so be careful
being swayed by immediate returns uh to
decide whether this is a good flexi Cap
Fund or not all right uh okay I want to
talk about one um the fund called
balanced Advantage fund because um of
course over here as well because we had
the SBI balanced Advantage fund which
was launched and boy did that one Garner
some massive flows almost 12 ,000 CR
rupees but even if we remove that there
is still compared to all the other
equity and debt mutual funds a good
amount of net invest interest in
balanced Advantage Funds now right now
as we speak Mr naui the markets are just
about hovering near their record high
levels uh debt funds as well at this
point of time there is um you know that
thing that okay yields may start going
up only up from here on so given the
scenario especially given that you know
you don't know where to invest and how
to put your money is this a good place
to start off balanced Advantage Funds
I think balance Advantage Funds have the
advantage uh and that's why I think the
the word in their name uh that they are
able to move uh you know their Equity
allocation Up and Down based on uh just
Market valuation each of the balanced
Advantage fund have slightly different
ways by which they determine whether
markets are cheap expensive moderate Etc
but they have formulas which are sort of
set and based on the formula
automatically the allocation of equity
sort of increases or comes down uh so to
that extent they remove the behavioral
bias uh where typically as an adviser
when markets are really down uh let's
take March of
2020 um and you had a really sharp fall
is when I would really come up to you as
an investor and say hey this is a good
time for you to invest the markets have
fallen 30% from on the top but if you
remember that time uh there's a fair
amount of fear and you say no no hang on
even though I have 100 more Rupees to
put in for Equity okay fine since you're
telling me so much I'll put 10 Rupees
out of that so I'm not really taking
advantage of the asset class I need to
be in now these balance advantages funds
did really well during that time because
when the markets fell in March 2020 and
by April they were at almost 90%
allocation in Equity uh and they really
captured most of the upside that was
there in the market however the formula
told them probably by October November
that means fairly early that the markets
are you know starting to be a little
more expensive so we should reduce our
allocation so these are funds which
don't give you the entire Equity upside
but they give you like a debt plus plus
type of return so you should get uh
double digit uh slow double digit type
of returns over a long period of time
and that's why I think uh this is
attracting people especially firsttime
investors because here I'm not you know
totally dependent on the advisor or the
timing of putting in a lump suum at one
go all in
equity okay I want to also you know
don't not not sticking it with then you
know Equity Funds but I also want to
talk about uh debt funds where um again
one category that's really catching my
attention is
the floater funds almost a net inflows
of close to 10,000 CR rupees in this one
um is is that a good way to invest in
debt funds right now considering the
fact that you know many are expecting
that okay interest rates will go higher
from here
on yeah I think it's it's a question of
where your view is in terms of interest
rate so if interest rates are expected
to go higher the logical thing to do is
to get onto floer type of funds uh
because they will help to uh sort of
hedge uh that sort of movement in
interest rates the other thing you would
do is to stay with funds which have a
lower duration because then the impact
of that higher interest rate is much
much lower and you are sort of better
off of course the rates of return for
these type of funds is not really very
high but just because you want to play
that interest rate game um I think if
the flo of fund is good my guess is that
if you do a little bit of deep dive a
lot of that money in the flo of funds
could possibly be institutional money
and not necessarily uh retail money uh
it could be high net worth individuals
uh and institutions so yes I think
that's a good way of playing the Dead
game for the time being if you do
believe that interest rates are going to
go
up okay all right so that's got to do
with how to go about investing in debt
funds let's do one thing let's take on
got some questions and queries from our
viewers then remember folks you can
connect with us on our email address the
money
show.tv uh let's take on board some
questions we've already got uh we've got
a question from Ragu who says I'm 58
years old I'd like to shift um from
fixed deposits to the access Focus 25
and would like to draw 5% every year
post the third year onwards through S
swp on a monthly basis um while s swp
when I'm doing my SW calc calculation I
can see Capital appreciating over a
period of 7 years please advise okay so
um you know what let's let's look at it
this way that he's got an FD he wants to
put it an access Focus 25 and then after
3 years he wants to withdraw
55% um every year what's your take is
this a good strategy for Ragu though
mind you he's not mentioned what are his
other investment strategies but let's
assume this is the only thing right now
that he has as his financial
plan yes so first and foremost uh you
know the uh he has to keep in mind that
you're moving from a safety uh to a
aggressive sort of investment because
you're going away from fixed deposit and
putting the money in equity uh I know
you have looked at a calculator and
seeing that you know Capital appreciates
over a period of seven years and this
mind you obviously is happened based on
past data there's no guarantee that that
past data is going to replicate itself
so so first and foremost are you open to
taking that extra risk uh by investing
in equity uh second so look at your
overall risk profile Etc the second
thing is that I don't know the Quantum
of money uh but I would not even if I
was to follow this strategy and I'm okay
with the risk I wouldn't put all my
money in one particular scheme uh
because we don't know how this scheme is
going to perform over the next 3 to five
or seven years in future you have known
that this is what what uh you know has
happened in the past your other question
saying that you're wanting to do this
for capital appreciation I'm not very
clear because capital appreciation you
let the money stay in a fund and let it
grow but I'm guessing you require some
income requirement which is why you're
saying you want to draw 5% in a year
after the third year onwards so you
might you know if you dealt with an
advisor be given other options other
than this route to meet your income
slash retirement requirements um so
that's my sort of overall take uh on
[Music]
this prizes
Zoom Angel broking is now Angel one
everyone deserves more speed Angel one
quick account opening stock market
investing investments in Securities
markets are subject to Market risks read
all the related documents carefully
before investing